<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <author email="stack at archive dot org">Michael Stack</author>
    <revision>$Id$</revision>
  </properties>
  <body>

<section name="Before you start...">
<p>Before you start, make sure you've satisfied all
<a href="requirements.html">requirements</a>.</p>
</section>

<section name="Running NutchWAX">
<p>Download a NutchWAX binary. See
<a href="http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=118427">sourceforge downloads page</a>.  Ungzip and untar.  Let the unpacked directory be
${NUTCHWAX} in all that follows (For how to build from source, see
<a href="srcbuild.html">Building from src</a> page).</p>

<subsection name="Indexing and searching a small collection - Using NutchWAX 0.4.2 or earlier (i.e pre-mapreduce NutchWAX)">
<p>Try out NutchWAX on a small collection of ARCs first.
<pre>% cd ${NUTCHWAX}
% chmod u+x ./bin/*
% ./bin/indexarcs.sh -h</pre>
<code>indexarcs.sh</code> is a wrapper script that will run through all the
indexing step.  It takes a bunch of options. To do the most basic indexing
operation, point it a few ARC files and let it run:
<pre>% ./bin/indexarcs.sh -s ${HOME}/arcs/ -d ${HOME}/nutch-data -c COLLECTION_NAME</pre>
This will build an index for you in <code>${HOME}/nutch-data</code> (-n says
do not run the deduplication step -- necessary if you are using nutchwax
    with WERA -- and the '-c' is the name of the collection the indexed
    content will belong to).
</p>
<p>
To search this index, copy the ${NUTCHWAX}/webapps/nutchwax.war file under
the ${TOMCAT}/webapps directory.  Then start tomcat FROM 
${HOME}/nutch-data, the directory you built the index in (Nutch by
default will use the current working directory of the tomcat container
when looking for the index to open).  Browse to the '/nutchwax' context on
your tomcat instance and try searches against the ARC content.
</p>
<p>To learn more about the indexing and searching process, see
<a href="operation.html">operation</a> and the <a href="faq.html">FAQ</a>.
</p>
</subsection>

<subsection name="wera">
    <p>You'll notice that clicking on a NutchWAX search result takes you 
    nowhere.  This is because NutchWAX by default has no means of
    rendoring the search hit out of the web archive collection.
    <a href="http://archive-access.sourceforge.net/projects/wera/">WERA</a> is an application that can do
    this for you. WERA is like the Internet Archive
    <a href="http://www.archive.org/web/web.php">Wayback Machine</a> except
    it also supports full text search (courtesy of NutchWAX). It is a php
    application for searching and browsing WACs.
    See the <a href="http://archive-access.sourceforge.net/projects/wera/">WERA</a> for how to install.
    </p>
</subsection>
</section>
</body>
</document>

