<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Help: Queries</title>
    <author email="stack at archive dot org">Michael Stack</author>
    <revision>$Id$</revision>
  </properties>
  <body>

<section name="Help: Queries">

<p>Generally, queries should work as they do in Google with many of the
same query parameters supported (if sometimes less completely). Query parameters include:
date, site, url, and type.
See <a href="http://archive-access.sourceforge.net/projects/nutch/faq.html#queryfields">Query
Fields</a> for a more complete list.
</p>

<subsection name="Terms are AND'ed together">
<p>Like Google, queries AND terms together so the query <code>Pope Rome</code>
will search for all documents with <code>Pope</code> AND <code>Rome</code> only.</p>
</subsection>

<subsection name="All terms except...(i.e. NOT)">
<p>To search for all documents that do not include a term, prefix the term
with a minus (or a 'NOT'). For example the query <code>Pope -Rome</code> will return
search results for documents that include the term <code>Pope</code> but NOT the
term <code>Rome</code>.
</p>
</subsection>

<subsection name="Dates and Date Ranges">
<p>Dates are always GMT and specified using 14 digits in the form
<code>yyyymmddHHMMSS</code> where <code>yyyy</code> is a 4 digit year,
<code>mm</code> is a two
digit month (zero-pad if month is single-digit), <code>dd</code> is
date, <code>HH</code> is two-digit hour, <code>MM </code>is
two-digit minute, and <code>SS</code> is two-digit seconds.</p>

<p>You cannot search by date alone. You must also supply a term as
part of your query. For example: <code>date:20051204000000 pope</code>
will return documents that include the term pope and that were
archived on the 4th of December, 2005 (at midnight).</p>
<p>To specify date ranges, pass two dates separated by a hyphen to the date
field. For example, the query 
<code>date:20041204000000-20051204000000 pope</code> will return documents that contain the term "pope" that were
archived between December 4th 2004 and the same day in 2005.
</p>
</subsection>

<subsection name="Sort By and Sort Order">
<p>To reorder the search results by date rather than relevance you need to
add the following to the end of the search query in your browser
location: <code>&amp;sort=date</code>  (Later we'll add an advanced search
page to preclude need of direct URL manipulation). For example, a search
using the term <code>katrina</code> will result generally in an entry in
the location bar of
the browser looking like this: <code>http://websearch.archive.org/collections/katrina/search.jsp?query=katrina</code>.
Append <code>&amp;sort=date </code>to sort the results by date: E.g. <code>http://websearch.archive.org/collections/katrina/search.jsp?query=katrina</code><code>&amp;sort=date</code>.
To sort by descending date order, append <code>&amp;reverse=true</code>:
E.g. <code>http://websearch.archive.org/collections/katrina/search.jsp?query=katrina</code><code>&amp;sort=date</code><code>&amp;reverse=true.</code>
</p>
</subsection>

<subsection name="Examples">
<p>Look for pdfs by adding <code>url:pdf</code> to your query or <code>type:pdf</code>.
</p>
</subsection>
<subsection name="Other Help Sources">
<p>See the <a href="http://archive-access.sourceforge.net/projects/nutch/faq.html#datesort">Querying
section on the NutchWAX</a> FAQ page as well as the <a href="http://wiki.apache.org/nutch/FAQ">Nutch FAQ</a>.</p>
</subsection>
</section>
</body>
</document>
