<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Building from source</title>
    <author email="stack at archive dot org">St.Ack</author>
    <revision>$Id$</revision>
  </properties>
  <body>

<section name="Before you start...">
<p>Before you start, make sure you've satisfied
<a href="requirements.html">requirements</a>.</p>
</section>

<section name="Building NutchWAX from src - Pre-mapreduce (i.e. Nutch-0.7 and NutchWAX 0.4.2 or earlier)">
<p>Do an anonymous svn checkout of the archive-access/projects/nutch project.
See <a href="http://sourceforge.net/svn/?group_id=118427">Subversion Access</a>
for instructions that will checkout the archive-access project.  NutchWAX
is in the archive-access/projects/nutch subdirectory.
Let ${NUTCHWAX} be this directory everafter.</p>

<p>Obtain the latest Nutch release.  See
    <a href="http://www.apache.org/dyn/closer.cgi/lucene/nutch/">nutch
    downloads</a>.
    The below has been tested working using nutch 0.7.0. Revert to
    this version of Nutch if problems building (Nutchwax will not
    work with release 0.6 of Nutch). Unbundle the nutch release  It usually
    untars as nutch-0.?.?.  The build scripts are looking for 'nutch' in 
the ${NUTCHWAX} directory so you need to
either rename nutch directory as Nutch or make a symbolic link from
nutch-0.?.? to Nutch.
If building against 0.7.1, you'll need to create the directory
<literal>${NUTCH_HOME}/src/plugins/nutch-extensionpoints/src/java</literal>
else the nutch ant build fails (There seem to be other issues running
nutchwax against nutch 0.7.1 that need looking into).
You'll may also have to update
${NUTCHWAX}/project.properties to rename the corenutch jar if building
against a nutch that is other than that which nutchwax is currently working
against.
</p>

<p>Symlink <literal>${NUTCHWAX}/nutch/conf/nutch-site.xml.template</literal> to 
${NUTCHWAX}/conf/nutch-site.xml. Doing this, there is only one nutch-site.xml
shared by core Nutch and by NutchWAX extensions.
<pre>   % cd ${NUTCH_HOME}/nutch/conf
    % mv  nutch-site.xml nutch-site.xml.original
    % ln -s ${NUTCHWAX}/conf/nutch-site.xml.template nutch-site.xml</pre>
The <literal>nutch-site.xml.template</literal> that is in ${NUTCHWAX} has
NutchWAX
specific configuration overrides as well as hardcodings of collection names and
the name of the archive host that holds archived pages. Edit these to suit your
environment particularly 'wax.host' and 'wax.collection'. The
NutchWAX search.jsp compounds these values to come up with the WAC URL
that shows as part of the search results under the 'other versions' link.
Don't worry if you don't know exact values at this stage. You can always
come back later to make adjustment.</p>

<p>Build Nutch (Anytime you make edits in base Nutch, redo this step).
<pre>   % cd ${NUTCHWAX}/nutch
    % ${ANT_HOME}/bin/ant compile jar war</pre>
Note: Fedora Core 3 has 1.5.x ant installed.  The Nutch build is 1.6.x ant.  I
used a local ant 1.6.2 install and passed '--noconfig' so we didn't reference
the fedora ant 1.5.x install.</p>

<p>Build NutchWAX.
<pre>   % cd ${ARCHIVE_ACCESS}
% ${ANT_HOME}/bin/ant compile jar war</pre>
</p>
<p>Under ${NUTCHWAX}/build you'll find the war file, classes and jars.</p>
<p>To produce the binary bundle, we use maven (The ant and maven build need
to be better unified).  Run 'maven dist'.</p>.

</section>
</body>
</document>

